I can defeat that Director!
倒せる
あの会長を
I won't let go!
One more round!
離さねえ
もうひと勝負
The curtain rises on Kaiji's
assault on the Director.
この黒幕
会長を討つ
Kaiji's final challenge begins!
カイジ
最後の挑戦が始まる
Conditions
ざわ
ざわー
もうひと勝負だ
One more round, I said!
Hey, you!
きさま
会長がお疲れだと
仰っているのが分からないのか！
Didn't you understand when the
Director said he was tired?!
So what?!
知ったことか！
うーむ
逃がさねえ
I won't let you escape!
Don't go too far!
図に乗りおって
だあ
もう一度勝負だ！
One more round!
You!
きさま！
待て
Wait.
まずこの手を離してもらおう
Firstly, will you let go
of my hand?
ここまで食い下がられては
Since you refuse to back down,
I have no choice.
仕方あるまい おい
Hey, you.
はい
駄目だ！
Yes, Sir!
- No!
- What is it?
何？
そいつはもうこりごりだ
断る！
I've had enough of that!
I refuse!
そうかそれでは
あれを
待て！
I see.
In that case...
- Bring the other...
- Wait!
もうそっちが用意するものは
I refuse to accept anything
that you've prepared!
お断りだ
信用できねえ
I can't trust you!
どんな仕掛けがしてあるか
分かったもんじゃないからな
I don't know what
sort of trap you've laid!
What?!
何？
覚えがないとは言わせねえ
I don't have to spell it out!
なるほど
I see.
なるほどな
Honestly...
But Kaiji,
that puts me in a fix.
しかしカイジ君
それは困ったのう
それで一体
どうしろと言うのだ
So, what exactly would you
like me to do?
If E-Card is out and
so is everything else,
Ｅカードも駄目
他に用意するものも駄目では
勝負のしようがないではないか
what will we gamble on?
I'm thinking.
考える
考える？
Thinking?
俺が何か
I might have an idea.
If he immediately proposed using
the tissue box lottery gamble,
すぐにティッシュ箱を使った
くじを提案しては
いかにもこちらが
用意していたようで
the opponent would suspect
a trap of some sort.
相手に疑念を抱かせる
The timing and context
of the suggestion,
言い出すタイミング
間合い
表情
and also his expression
must be as natural as possible.
これらが自然に流れなければ
Or he might blow this chance!
全て水泡
いわばこれもまたギャンブル
In other words,
this is a gamble in itself.
He has to take calculated steps
in drawing his opponent closer...
自分と相手の間合い
呼吸をはかり
相手を自分の思惑の中へ引き込む
...and finally, into his plan.
Paper towels...
ペーパータオル
Just now, Tonegawa used those to
wipe the blood from the table.
さっき利根川がテーブルの
血を拭くのに使った
ペーパータオルだ
ふん
That, and also... a ruler!
それと
定規
この２つを持ってきてくれ
Bring me these two items.
Kaiji gets to work!
カイジ
動く
He starts making
the lottery tickets,
己の戦略
その勝利
which are the basis for
the victory he had planned!
全てを支える土台
くじ作りへ
He was so nonchalent
about it... How clever!
さりげないけど
うまい
Despite forcing the Director
into a gamble...
会長に勝負を迫り
承諾を取りながらも
he still hasn't said a
word about the wager.
掛け金については何も言わない
This was just in case the
black suits were to bring...
無論
これはこのあと黒服が
...a tissue box without
the fake winning lot inside.
当たりくじが仕掛けられていない
ティッシュ箱
すなわち
Namely, one of the smaller
and more compact tissue boxes.
圧縮タイプの小さいサイズを
持ってきた場合に備えてのこと
That would result in the gamble
being based purely on luck,
仕掛けのない
運次第の勝負になった場合
in which case Kaiji would
wager only a small amount.
カイジは
掛け金の額を低く設定する
それに
何をやるかを宣言せずに
Also, it was clever of him
to begin making the lots...
...before declaring anything.
まずくじ作りを始めたのもうまい
If he were to propose a
lottery gamble right away,
もし先に
くじで勝負するって言ってたら
things might have been
complicated.
多分
厄介なことになってた
例えば
くじにする紙は
向こうが用意するとか言って
For example, the opponent
might bring out writing pads...
レポート用紙とかメモ用紙を
出してきたかもしれない
...or note books
in order to prepare the lots.
If so, the tissue box scheme
would go to waste!
そうなったら
ティッシュ箱の仕掛けは無意味
And that would be the end.
万事休す
Even for the mark
on the winning lot,
この当たりを示す丸の印だって
相手に星だのバツにするだの
言い出されたら
the opponent might request
to use a star or cross instead.
That would spoil everything.
それで全てが破綻
That's why he must create
the lots without a word!
だから
何も言わずに
まず
くじ作りなんだ
He's preparing the lots while
the opponent is still unclear...
何をしているのか
相手によく分からない状況での
...on what the gamble is about.
くじ作り
偶然そうしてるんじゃない
All this isn't done randomly...
全てカイジさんの戦略
Every detail is a part of
Kaiji's strategy!
もう戦いは始まっている
The battle has already begun!
Darn it!
くそ
After drawing
the fake winning lot,
仕込んだ当たりくじを引いたあと
how will I deceive them
out of finding the genuine one?
箱の中に残る本当の当たりくじを
どうやってごまかすかだが
After drawing the winning lot,
俺は当たりくじを引いたら
派手に箱を掲げて振り回す
I'll show off by hoisting it above
my head and emptying its contents.
当然
くじは部屋中に散乱する
Naturally, the lots would
be scattered.
でも
その散乱した中に
当たりくじがあるんでしょう
But won't the real winning lot
be among the scattered ones?
That'd be as good as
letting them find it, right?
見つかったら
同じことじゃないですか
だから
前もって当たりくじを
何枚か床にまいておくのさ
That's why I'll leave
several other winning lots...
...on the floor in advance.
くじを作るとき
While making the lots, I'll make
a lot of "flawed" ones...
最初の何枚かを書き損じて
...and discard them
onto the floor.
それを床に投げ捨てる
あるはずのない当たりくじが
見つかっちゃまずいが
If they find a winning lot that
shouldn't be there, it'd be doom.
何枚か印の付いたくじが
But if they don't know how many
there are on the floor,
床に落ちてたとなれば
ごまかせる
I'd be able to
bluff my way through.
それが２枚だったか３枚だったか
なんていうのは水掛け論
So long as they don't know
the exact number,
言い逃れる道はいくらでもあるさ
I can talk my way through it.
Darn it!
くそ
今
カイジさんは
懸命に積み上げている
Now Kaiji is doing his best
to set up the conditions.
In order to ensure his victory,
必勝のための仕組み
鬼を殺す策略のかけらを
he must piece together
the plan to slay the devil!
顔を伏しゆっくりと
Pacing himself and ensuring that
everything is foolproof!
しかし
確実に積み上げている
This victory can't be
based on luck.
勝つことは
偶然じゃない
Winners don't win by accident!
勝つ者は勝つべくして
勝っているんだ
勝つ道
勝つ力を気付かず戦えば
負けて当然
Winners make preparations
to ensure their victory.
It's not by coincidence but
rather, through concrete steps.
勝つってことは
もっと具体的な行為の
延長線にある
そういう意識を
I'm nowhere near that level...
俺はもっていなかった
But Kaiji is different!
カイジさんは違う
Kaiji is...
カイジさんは
This will do.
これでよし
おう
見ての通りだ
As you can see,
there's one winning lot...
１枚当たりくじと
大量の外れくじ
...amidst many blank ones.
I'll mix this and
we'll take turns drawing.
これを混ぜ
かわりばんこに引く
先に当たりを引いた方が勝ち
The first to draw
the winning lot, wins.
シンプルだろ
ふふん
Isn't it simple?
All that's left is to find
something to put the lots in.
あとは
何にこのくじを入れるか
おい
何か袋か箱を用意してやれ
Hey! Get him a bag or
box of some sort.
Yes, Sir.
The trap is nearly complete.
仕掛けは大詰め
駄目だ
これは中身が透ける
それに
This won't do!
You can see through it.
Also, this bag is your
personal property.
このかばんは
もともとそっちの持ち物
細工があるかもしれん
きさまいい加減に
You might have rigged it,
who knows?
Hey! That's enough already!
もっとまっさらな
It has to be something neutral!
何か
あれだ
That's it.
We'll use that.
あれを使おう
Not that one!
そいつは駄目だ ああ？
まだ開封されていない
Get a new one that
hasn't been opened yet.
新品がいい
会長！
Director!
持ってきてやれ
ははあ
Bring him one.
Yes, Sir!
ここまでは
カイジさんの思惑通りいってる
Up till now, everything has
gone according to Kaiji's plan.
問題はあの黒服が
くじを仕込んだ
The issue is if he would bring
the bigger tissue box variety...
大きい方のティッシュ箱を
持ってくるかどうか
...containing the fake lot.
It was the only factor
left to chance,
こればっかりは
人知の及ばない運の世界
that he has no control over.
もし小さい方を持ってきたら
What if he brings
the smaller one?
ざわ
ざわー
Alright!
やった
これでいいのか
Will this do?
Yeah...
Wait!
待った
開ける前に見せてくれ
Show it to me
before opening it.
まさかとは思うが
細工してる可能性だってある
Although unlikely, it might
have been tampered with.
おいきさま
きさまどこまで
見せてやれ
Hey, you!
That's going too far!
Let him see it.
やりすぎたか
Has he overreacted?
かえって会長に疑われたかも
Maybe the Director
suspects something...
よし
It's fine.
そっちも確認してくれ
You should check it too.
どうしてそんなことを
Why did he do that?!
What if he discovered
the set-up?!
そんなことして
仕掛けを見破られたら
問題なかろう
There doesn't seem to
be any problem.
開封するぞ
I'm opening it.
I see!
Could this also be...?
そうか
まさかこれも
This too
was part of Kaiji's plan.
これもまたカイジの計算である
If Kaiji alone were to
inspect the box,
カイジだけが調べれば
不自然と
疑惑を持たれる恐れもあるが
it would be unfair and
might appear suspicious.
Having one's opponent also
examine the match conditions...
相手にも調べさせることによって
勝負前の双方の確認
...is a necessary step.
必然の行為ととれる
The main factor...
そして重要なのは
開封前に
相手にチェックさせたこと
...is for the opponent to check
the box before it is opened.
Otherwise, if the box was inspected
after it had been opened,
つまり
開封後
ティッシュを抜いた後に
箱をのぞかれれば
くじの存在がばれてしまう
the fake lot
might be discovered.
Both parties must check the box
before it is opened.
双方がチェックするタイミングは
開封前しかない
カイジはまず
自分がチェックすることで
By checking the box first,
Kaiji creates a natural flow.
自然な流れを作り
相手を巻き込み
This was to draw the
opponent...
問題ないという
言葉まで引き出した
...into agreeing that
there were no problems.
完璧だ
すごみさえ感じる
It's perfect. I'm amazed.
勝つ人間とは
これ程までに用意周到に
Are all winners so meticulous
in planning out every step?
考え尽くしてるのか
置いてくれ
Put it down.
用意はできたぜ
会長さん
Everything is prepared,
Mr Director.
駄目だなあ
これは
This won't do.
なああ？
駄目だなあこれは
どういうことだ
What do you mean?
面白くない
It's not interesting.
手間取った割りに
あまりにも単純すぎる
This is too simple given
the amount of effort you put in.
大の大人が眠気を押して
It's not enough for two adult
men trying not to fall asleep...
明け方間近に
やるほどのものではない
...in the wee hours
of the morning.
とはいえ
Then again, this was your
personal request, Kaiji,
ここまで私を楽しませてくれた
カイジ君の
たっての頼みだ
and you gave me
so much entertainment.
やらぬとは言わぬが
ざわー
I won't refuse to play.
ただし
やるには条件が３つある
ざわ
However, if I were to play,
there would be three conditions.
条件？
ざわ
Conditions?
何
大したことではない
Don't worry,
it's not a big deal.
You'll understand when you
hear what they are.
聞けば至極
当然のこと
カイジ君なら
理解してくれることばかりだ
I'm sure you'd find them
quite normal, Kaiji.
言ってみろよ
Let's hear them.
条件の１つ目は
The first condition is related
to the rules of this game.
その当たりくじについての
取り決め
いかさま防止のためのな
It's to prevent cheating.
To prevent cheating?
いかさま防止のため？
見てみろ
Look at this...
この我々の運命を握る
当たりくじのかぼそさ
Our fates rest upon such a
frail slip of paper,
まさに吹けば飛ぶようだ
which can be easily
blown away.
だからこちらでいろいろと
保護せねばならん
That's why I must protect
my own chances.
まず第一に
団子の禁止
Firstly, it cannot be rolled up.
こんなものは丸めてしまえば
指の間はもとより
Rolled up like this, it can be
hidden under your fingernails...
爪の間にも隠せる
...or anywhere in your palm.
故に
こんな丸まった状態の
当たりくじは
Hence, we'll not accept
a lot that is crumpled up.
認めないことにしよう
これを認めてしまえば
引いたふりをして
If this were allowed,
you could produce a fake lot...
実は髪の毛や耳の穴に
あらかじめ仕組んだものを
...from your hair or
behind your ear,
当たりくじと称して
引いてくることもあり得る
while pretending to draw one.
お分かりか
Do you understand?
なるほどな
認めよう
団子は禁止だ
Yes.
I accept that crumpled lots
will not be allowed.
ははは 付け加えるなら
くじを引くときは当然
腕をまくり
In addition, one's sleeves
must be rolled up...
さらに引く寸前
互いに指の股を開いて
...when drawing from the box,
and fingers spread for
the other party to check.
手のひらのチェック
文句あるまい
No problem there, right?
No.
では条件の２つ目
As for the second condition,
これは少々
虫のいい頼みなんだが
it may seem rather selfish,
先行権をわしに譲ってもらいたい
but I would like
the right to draw first.
何っ？
What?
つまり
しょっぱなに
くじを引くのはわし
In other words,
I'll be drawing the first lot.
ということにしてもらいたい
I want you to grant
me this request.
ええ？馬鹿な！
そういうことは普通
I-Impossible!
That's usually settled over
a round of Rock Paper Scissors!
公平に
じゃんけんとかで決めるもんだ！
もっともだ
だが今回の場合
I agree with you.
But I've acceded to so many
of Kaiji's requests this time.
ここまでわしはカイジ君の要望を
全面的に受け入れてきた
Not only have I accepted
his challenge,
言われるままに勝負を受け
そちらが用意したくじでの勝負も
I've also accepted the idea of
a lottery gamble.
受け入れた
我ながらあきれかえるほどの
お人よしぶりだ
I've been kind-hearted so far.
それなのに少ない確率とはいえ
Even though the
chances are low,
if Kaiji draws the winning lot
on his first try,
もし
しょっぱなにカイジ君が
当たりくじを引きでもしたら
わしは一度もくじを引くことなく
この勝負は終わってしまう
the gamble would end without
me getting even a single try.
あまりといえば
あまりの話ではないか
Well, that is something
that's very unlikely.
それだけは避けたいのだ
何としても
But it is what I wish
to avoid, no matter what.
カイジさん
Kaiji...
嫌なら
わしは降りるだけのこと
If you don't like it,
I'll just refuse your gamble.
くそっ
Darn it!
足元を見やがって
He's making use of the fact
that I have no control over this!
もっとも
こっちが先行と
決まってたわけじゃない
In any case,
I didn't plan to draw first.
一度くらいなら
One draw should be enough.
好きにしろ
カイジさん！
Do as you wish.
Kaiji!
理解してもらえてありがたい
Thank you for being
so understanding.
さて３つ目
最後の条件だが
Now, the third and
final condition.
肝心な掛け金についてだ
あはっ
It's the crucial factor,
which is the wager.
カイジ君の持ち金
万
Kaiji, you have
20 million in cash.
そうだ
こいつをそっくり賭ける
That's right. I'll wager
the whole amount.
足りんな
ええ？足りない？
It's not enough.
Not enough?!
足りない分はわしの方で調整する
I'll make adjustments for
the insufficient amount.
調整？
Adjustments?
ずばり１億といかんか
How about making it
100 million instead?
１億だと？
100 million...?
That's right.
そうだ
そっそんな額
むちゃくちゃだ！
T-That's a ridiculous amount!
はした金では燃えん
A meagre amount like that
is nothing to me.
釣り合わぬ金額でわしにとっても
The amount is above
what you have...
間尺に合わんと分かっていながら
...and might be a waste
of my time,
それでも
燃えぬギャンブルよりはマシ
but it's better than a
gamble with no thrill.
あれを
- Bring that here.
- Yes!
こっこいつ
この男
This man is up to no good!
自覚しておる
I am well aware of it.
わしの脳は既に焼かれておる
The fact that my brain
is messed up.
常軌などというものは
とうに失せておる
I've gone off my rocker
since a long time ago.
普通の凡庸な刺激では燃えん
Ordinary stimulus
has no effect on me.
だって
カイジさんの持ち金は
2000万だけ
B-But Kaiji
has only 20 million!
That's right,
he doesn't have money.
そう
金はない
差額8000万
I'll have Kaiji bet on
something else...
カイジ君には
金以外を賭けてもらう
...to make up for the
difference of 80 million.
金以外？
Something else
instead of money?
普通１本につき
これほど大きな値は付けんのだが
Normally, I wouldn't attach such
a great value to just one round.
カイジ君が
ここまで勝ち残ってきた勇者
But Kaiji is an exception
who has won his way thus far.
クズとは格が違う
He is of a different category
from those trash.
そこに敬意を表して
And in order to show
my respect for him,
I've placed a ridiculously
huge price on it.
破格の値を付けよう
１本につき2000万
Each one is worth 20 million.
もし負ければ差額の8000万
And if he loses,
the 80 million difference...
カイジ君がその指４本によって
...will be repaid with
four of Kaiji's fingers.
清算してもらおう
悪くない話だろう？
Not a bad deal, isn't it?
This time, if Kaiji wins,
今回カイジ君が勝てば
さっき橋を渡ったときのように
I won't do what I did during
the bridge crossing earlier,
チケットによる引き換えだ何だと
ケチなことは言わん
where a ticket was given
in exchange for money.
I'll pay you
right away in cash.
その場できっちり払おう
キャッシュでな
うはあ
余程の幸運か才能
Very good luck,
あるいは人生何十年もの
月日を費やしての労働
exceptional talent
or decades of hard work.
この３つのいずれかを
そそぎ込まねば
If you have
none of the above,
決して得ることのできぬ金
億
a sum of 100 million
can never be achieved.
これが一瞬で
カイジ君のものになる
And this can be Kaiji's
in an instant, if he wins.
勝てばな
ねじ曲がる
Distorting, distorting!
世界をねじ曲げるほどの
A powerful magnetic field
that distorts its surroundings...
強力な磁場を放つ金
...is released from that
huge sum of money!
空間を
人の心を
A demon that distorts
and draws in...
ねじ曲げ吸い寄せる魔物
金
...its surroundings
and human hearts!
Money, the most dangerous,
yet the sweetest evil!
最も危険で
最も甘美な魔物
１億
圧倒的な金
A staggering amount
of 100 million...
それが目の前
つかめば届くところにある
...is now before his eyes
and is within reach!
ただし
However...
負ければ持っていかれる
この指
His fingers are at stake
if he loses!
They will be excised
at the root!
根元から４本！
So, what will it be, Kaiji?
さあどうする？カイジ君
指をなくす上に2000万も取られ
Not only will I lose my fingers,
but I'll lose
the 20 million too...
残るのは借金と痛み
All that will remain are
debts and pain.
壊滅的敗北
A complete utter defeat.
手持ちの2000万が
みすぼらしく見えちまう大金
That huge amount makes
my 20 million look shabby.
With my hourly pay of 900 yen,
I'll never attain it.
時給900円の俺が
どんだけ働いても
働いても
No matter how hard I work,
no matter how hard I work...
働いても
たどり着けない金
I'll never achieve that amount.
With this, I can start all over!
これだけあればやり直せる
I can start over from
the beginning!
全てを
最初から
俺の願い通りの人生にやり直せる
I can rebuild my life again
just the way I want it.
いけ
怖いのは
Go for it!
The only thing to fear...
やつが一回目に
当たりを引いてしまうこと
...is if he draws the winning lot
on the first try!
It's not entirely impossible but
he has almost no chance of that.
あり得ないことじゃないが
限りなく０に近い確率
As long as I don't get unlucky,
I'm sure to win this!
そんな不運さえなければ
勝てる
勝てるんだ
カイジさん…
I can win!
Kaiji...
It's fine. I'll do it.
大丈夫だ
いける
でもっ
- B-But...
- It'll be fine!
いいんだ
もし負けたら
If you lose...
そりゃ考えないわけじゃねえ
It's true that it's not
entirely impossible.
負ける不運を
まるで考えないわけじゃねえ
It's not entirely impossible
to suffer bad luck.
However...
けど
I can repaint my life again
from scratch!
この俺の人生を
完全に塗り替えられる
これだけの金を目の前にして
The money to do so
is right before my eyes!
降りられるか
Can I let it pass by?
ＧＯだ！俺は指を掛ける！
Go!
I'll bet my fingers!
ぐふーひひひひー
くるか
Oh, is that so?
カイジ
狂気の夜
Kaiji's night of insanity.
その最終局面が動き出す
He makes his move during
this final scene!
ざわ
次回
蒼白
Next, Investment
ざわー